June 1986

PERSONAL DETAILS

Full Name: Dr Peter Walton

Address: 7 Loring Street, Newton Heath, Manchester, M40 1WU

Email: waltonpeter536@gmail.com

Position Sought: Technical management, specialising in payment and other integrated solutions.

A highly motivated, experienced technical manager with a long history of successful projects, delivering excellent customer solutions. Many of these were integration projects and involved high levels of innovation to deliver new services. Key management skills include team leadership, motivation, and direction. During the development of new solutions, a keen understanding of customer requirements and the ability to envisage processes and solutions to meet these are essential. Technical skills include a strong understanding of technologies and how they lead to excellent solutions requiring low levels of administration and maintenance. Recent interests include machine learning and artificial intelligence. This has led to the completion of several certified courses.

EDUCATION, TRAINING AND DOMAIN KNOWLEGE

University of Manchester: First class Bsc. Hons in Mathematics Sept 1982

PhD. in Mathematics

My PhD. thesis was completed as part of a CASE award and was concerned with a

number of problems in water waves and the berthing action of ships.

Project Management: PRINCE2 certified at foundation and practitioner level (expires February 2023).

Full Stack Development: Codecademy PRO, Full Stack Engineering (88% complete).

Data Science/AI: I IBM professional certificate in Python Data Science (completed Jan 2020).

Total Quality Management: This course was part of the BP TQM program, conducted at McBride's.

Domain Knowledge: Payment solution, material control systems, manufacturing systems, trained in

machine learning and artificial intelligence (Python, PyTorch).

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Property renovation, training provision, personal retraining and COVID isolation: Jan 2019 - Present

Following a major change in strategy at Verifone, a number of severance packages were negotiated with senior staff. I received one of these packages. This allowed consideration of a number of things that had been in abeyance and movement of working location back to Manchester:

March 2020 to *Date* - Isolating due to COVID risk measures. Studying on Codecademy PRO, Career Path Full Stack Engineering course (88% complete).

August 2019 to March 2020 - Provided IT training cover in the Manchester region for a London-based IT training company. The training subjects were SQL Server and Java. Originally it was anticipated that supporting this training would require approximately three days per week. Unfortunately, the training requirements did not grow to this level. In March 2020, the COVID crisis lead the company to an online only strategy. No further face-to-face training will be required in Manchester.

September 2019 to Feb 2020 - Retraining - Following a renovation of the property (see below), it was possible to look at some retraining. This was in the areas of machine learning and artificial intelligence and took the form of an IBM professional qualification in 'Python Data Science'. which was completed in January 2020. This required the completion of five online courses including a real-life project concerning complaints to the New York housing department (final notebook reports available). The next logical course was the IBM professional qualification in 'Deep Learning' two courses have been completed and a third started.

Prince2 Foundation and Practitioner course – this was completed in February 2020 and the practitioner element is valid until February 2013.

January 2019 to August 2019 - Property development - During my time at Verifone, I had purchased a property that, unfortunately, needed renovation. Oversaw a back-to-brick renovation of the property including full re-plastering, rewiring, renovation of central heating, fitting of a new bathroom, fitting of a new kitchen and, a small amount of groundwork.

Trintech/Verifone: March 2001 - Dec 2018

Trintech/Verifone is an international supplier of end-to-end payment solutions and PAS services. At peak, Veifone had over 230 self-hosting clients, many of who were tire 1 and 2 companies. Toward the end of this period, Veifone also provided a PAS service. While at Trintech/Verifone four different roles were fulfilled:

Product Delivery Manager (2015 - 2018) - Responsible for requirements gathering, estimation, and planning of roadmaps for all Verifone UK products. This needed to balance consideration of four elements:

- · Corporate strategy on product evolution,
- Response to emerging technologies (mobile payment etc.),
- Identification and management of changes driven by payment standards and practices (card scheme mandates, PCI, P2PE, etc.),
- Consideration and assessment of customer-requested changes.

This required the product team to liaise with all departments within the Verifone as well as the card schemes, acquirers, and Verifone/Customer QSAs.

The roadmaps were developed using a strict PLC (product life cycle) framework. The initial version of this framework was strictly waterfall but was enhanced into a form that supported Agile interaction with the associated stakeholders. At all-time in the product delivery, close coordination with the product management, development teams, and end customers was essential and was assured.

Services Manager (2006 – 2015) - This involved running a combined team of project managers, product specialists, and deployment engineers. The purpose of this team was to provide all services to support solution integration, certification, and deployment in conjunction with Verifone's partners and customers. This team was run on a P&L basis with strict attention to revenue realisation and resource utilisation. Key industry deliverables during this time frame were contactless payments, PCI compliance, and P2PE certification.

Development Team Leader (2002 – 2006) - The role here was to manage a development team that contributed major components to emerging EMV payment solutions. These were terminal software, middleware components, and an estate management solution. The team was also responsible for the support of integration projects with many partners. The solutions were deployed in the following environments - PAS, retail, petro, kiosk, and e-commerce. Many of these solutions were for tier one companies and involved integration with many major point-of-sale suppliers.

Implementation co-ordinator (2001 - 2002) - This involved supporting the deployment of the TopUp solution developed for E-commercell (see below) to additional customers. Each of these deployments represented the launch of a national e-TopUp service. The countries involved were - Spain, the United States, Holland, Bahrain, Dominican Republic, and Albania.

Standout Projects -

Major UK retailer

This company began using Trintech/Verifone payment solutions in the early days of EMV. They have used three generations of Verifone solutions which have assisted with a number of strategic achievements as well as providing the payment services required:

- A solution where each POS had a fully integrated payment device running APAC40. All payment services were achieved through a shared ISDN link with GPRS backup.
- A fully integrated solution where all POS and terminals were managed by a store controller running PAYware Link as middleware. The solution included client switching to ensure full resilience. All payments were completed by a self-hosted implementation of Payware Merchant (Verifone's payment transaction host).
- Enhancement to the previous solution to introduce contactless payments, a new card acceptance device, and to leverage Payware Merchants (Verifone's payment transaction host) PCI certification.

Achievements supported by solutions -

- Very quick online payments at the point-of-sale (peaking at 20,000 full EMV payments per day).
- Reliable end-of-day processing and associated reconciliation processes.
- Movement to a fully integrated solution and all the benefits that follow.
- Very early adoption of contactless payments (2nd in UK retail).
- Simplification of PCI certification.
- Flexibility of POS suppliers.
- Support for sustained 30% year-on-year growth.

Early in this relationship, the role was as a development manager with the responsibility to manage the design and development and roll-out of the required solution. Later my role became that of services manager, responsible for the requirement gathering, delivery, certification, roll-out, and piloting of the later generations of the solutions.

Major UK petrol distributor

Trintech/Verifone provided this company with a set of payment solutions for both dealer-owned-dealer-operated (DODO) and company-owned-company-operated (COCO) petrol stations.

The COCO solution involved integration with incumbent point-of-sale and card acceptance devices by means of the Payware Link integration framework.

The deployments at the DODO sites represented a major rationalisation exercise moving the sites away from an incongruous mix of solutions. This also allowed a single business model to be employed across the DODO and COCO sites. Two main solutions were deployed at the DODO sites:

• An in-shop solution, that consisted of a store controller running Payware Link, a variety of POS solutions, and a standard card acceptance device. To allow easy integration with a variety of

- incumbent POSs, Payware Link provided an IFSF (International Forecourt Standards Forum) implementation, and each POS provider integrated to that interface..
- An unattended payment solution that used Payware Link to integrate with in-store POS platforms as
 well as the petrol pump controller. This demanded close working with the POS provider and
 provider of the pump controller. Again the IFSF standard was used for integration with the POS.

This was a major project including several development sub-projects and multiple certifications with the required acquirers and the fuel card providers. Loyalty cards were also supported within the solution. The solution was also unique in that the companies fuel cards supported online PIN and involved the secure remote delivery of DUKPT keys to each card acceptance device.

A full range of remote management mechanisms was delivered as part of the solution.

The role within this project was development manager with the responsibility to manage the design and development and certification the required solutions.

Prior to 2001 -

The information below summarises work prior to 2001:

E-Commercell: (contract position) Electronic mobile top-up solution- *implementation coordinator*.

Diva-Is Specialised sales solutions – *development manager*.

McBrides Plc MRP2 and other manufacturing systems - development team leader,

senior business system consultant, and technical manager.

Redpath Engineering Material control systems – *senior developer*.

Eurosoft Systems UNIX/Informix software house – *development team leader*.

Manchester University Mathematical modelling – *research assistant*.

Further details are available upon request.

SPECIFIC SKILLS

Methodologies: Experience of the following environments - Agile using Scrum, PRINCE II,

UML, various scaled methodologies using UML exhibits, E-R diagrams, Entity Life Histories, Functional Decompositions and Dataflow Diagrams. VDM.

Operating Systems: All major releases of Windows, UNIX variants, LINUX, embedded OSs, OS/2,

VM/CMS, MS/DOS. Familiar with capabilities and use of VMware.

Languages/Packages: "C", "C++", Python, Matlab, LATEX, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Office,

Microsoft Project, Delphi V2 & V3, Informix-SQL, Informix-4GL & Debugger (standard engine), Crystal Reports V6, Fortran, NAG Libraries, GINO graphics,

OS/2 Database Manager II, OS/2 LAN Server.

Business Packages: Chameleon in Manufacturing, Scheduler from Manugistics.

INTERESTS

In my free time, I enjoy badminton, horse riding, real ale and reading.

***** END OF DOCUMENT *****